# **ELAVANATT REKHA**

## Web Developer, Former Educator

§ 9550314502 

② elavanattrekha@gmail.com 
② github.com/Rekha-Elavanatt 

③ Emerald Residency, Suncity

#### **SKILLS**

## **Technical Skills**

Javascript HTML CSS React

Bootstrap

#### Soft Skills

Collaboration and Team work

Team Management and Organisation

Adaptability

Strong Communication

## **PROJECTS**

# (Tech Stack - Javascript, Bootstrap, Html, Css)

# To-Do App

# **=** 04/2024

- App.git https://github.com/Rekha-Elavanatt/To-Do-
- Built a functional to-do app which allows the user to add the items into the to-do list along with the due date and delete after completion.

# Portfolio

## **=** 03/2024

- https://github.com/Rekha-Elavanatt/My-Portfolio.git
- Built a portfolio with a fuctional home page, which provides basic information, and a contact form embeded using bootstrap.

## Calculator

## **#** 02/2024

- https://github.com/Rekha-Elavanatt/Calculator.git
- Built a functional calculator which performs basic mathematical operations.

## Cricket Game

# **m** 02/2024

- ${\boldsymbol{\mathscr{O}}}_{\text{Game.git}}^{\text{https://github.com/Rekha-Elavanatt/Cricket-}}$
- Built a functional cricket game in which a bat, ball and stump is to be clicked to score points which will be displayed directly on the screen. The scores will also be stored in the local storage.

## **HOBBIES**



Reading



**Drawing and Painting** 



Practice Guitar

# SUMMARY

With five years of experience in Education sector, currently shifting my focus towards growth in IT sector. Looking to start the career as an entry-level software engineer with a reputed firm driven by technology. I believe that with the training recieved for last few months on front end technologies, I have developed my skills strong in design and integration with intuitive problem-solving skills along with the ability to translate business requirements into technical solutions. Passionate about implementing and launching new projects.

## **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Engineering (64%)

Sridevi Women's Engineering College

**=** 2015 - 2019

# Diploma in Elementary Education (78%)

National Institute of Open Schooling

**=** 2017 - 2019

# Intermediate (93%)

Sri Chaitanya Junior Kalasala

**=** 2013 - 2015

# Secondary School Certificate (92%)

Prema Vijayan High School

**=** 2013

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Educator

## Sri Chaitanya Techno School

**=** 2022 - 2023

Social Studies

- Offered 8+ classes per semester to meet graduation needs of current high school class
- Aided department in designing curriculum maps and assessments for 10-14 units of instruction
- $\cdot$   $\,$  Ensured proper classroom management for 20-30 students
- Piloted 10+ learning management and data tracking platforms and evaluated their strengths and weaknesses

## Educator

# Prema Vijayan High School

**=** 2019 - 2022

Subjects Handled - Social Studies (High School), Science (Primary)

- Stepped forward mid-year to teach chemistry and physical science to 180 students
- Developed novel activities on a low budget to teach 7th and 8th grade science
- · Organised the annual award and grade 10 farewell ceremony in 2020

## Treasurer

# Prema Vijayan Social Welfare Association

**=** 2019 - 2022

- Managed finances and facilitated transactions made on behalf of the society made up of over 300 students
- Created and managed the student activities budget; manage all funds raised and coordinate scholarship
- · Supervised budget and kept aggregate expenditures 3% under budget

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**



# Kuchipudi Dancer

Trained in Kuchipudi under the guidance of Dr.Bhavana Pedaprolu, Mrs. INDIA cultural ambassador 2019, Mrs INDIA Telangana 2019, Director Sarada Kalakshetra, founder of World Kuchipudi Day.



# Participant of International Kuchipudi Dance Convention

Participated in the Mahabrundanatyam organised by Silicon Andhra on 4th International Kuchipudi Dance Convention - Navataram Natyatarangam.



# YouTube Channnel - @ThatMalluPilla

Started Vlogging in Jan 2024. I share my daily lifestyle vlogging experiences on my channel along with Mandala Arts Shorts. Regularly improving my editing skills helps me in understanding more about designing and presentation.